Shubham Agrawal

Data Analyst

Data Analyst with 3 years of experience executing data-driven solutions to increase efficiency, accuracy and utility to the teams. Give action-oriented solutions to complex business problems. Excellent understanding of business operations and analytics tools for effective data analysis. Communication and coordination experience in oral and written approaches with customers and internal stakeholders.

Mathura, India

(+91) 7251004418

M agrawalshubh932@gmail.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/shubham-agrawal-9a0b2b120/

https://medium.com/@shubh932

https://shubh-932.github.io/portfolio-website/

LANGUAGES

English Full Professional Proficiency

Hindi Full Professional Proficiency

SKILLS

Languages : Python (OOP), SQL

Libraries : NumPy, Pandas, Matplotlib, Seaborn, Streamlit

BI Tools : PowerBI, Apache Superset

Business Statistics : Descriptive + Inferential

Web Scraping : BeautifulSoup, Selenium

MS Office : Excel, Word, Powerpoint

Web Development : HTML5, CSS3, Flask

Other Skills : Salesforce Admin, Sharp Business Analytical Skills

EXPERIENCE

Axtria India Pvt Limited, Noida

Associate

Jan 2022 - PRESENT

- Created a Call Plan for the Primary Care Sales Team of the client ensuring that best targets are selected and appropriate calls are assigned. Also performed certain checks to compare the generated Call Plan health against the previous quarter Call Plan.
- Patient Data Analytics: Analyzed patient journey to identify physician opportunity to the client based on patient history, diagnosis, procedures etc.
- Build **Referral Networks** to track interconnectedness of HCPs of different specialties thereby 1) helping field teams to uncover new opportunities and preparing them better for upcoming customer engagements and 2) ensuring that patients receive best care possible.
- Automated Data Transfer (DT) process using python thereby saving 45 mins of the client.
- **Problem**: Manual validation is done post copy process of call plan and profiling objects to ensure data is correctly copied from the last cycle that took 36 hours. Solution: Created validation summary report with comparison of data count of past and present cycle using python. Now the objective is achieved in 10 minutes.
- Configured SalesIQ product to client using Salesforce.
- Current Project : Doing API integrations using Python.

Doubtbuddy, Gurugram

Data Analyst

May 2020 - Jan 2022

- Product Management: Maintained supply and demand to focus on FRT and quality. Checked product metrics like DAU, MAU, retention, daily active time and referrability. Guided tutor onboarding team to meet the requirement of tutors on the platform.
- Statistical Analysis: Queried the data for the problem statement using MySQL and visualized them thus produced actionable insights. Used correlation, standard deviation, regression, normal distribution and confidence interval.
- Created **dashboards** to track above metrics using Superset.
- Last Project: Worked with AI team- monitored the performance of OCR (recommendation engine of DoubtBuddy).

EDUCATION

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Visit my portfolio website

Bachelor of Technology in Computer Science & Engineering JSSATE, Noida

2014 - 2018

CERTIFICATES

- Google Data Analytics Professional Certificate, GOOGLE + Coursera
- Data Analysis with Python: Zero to Pandas, Jovian.ml + freecodecamp.org